<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on RÜTS</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on RÜTS</description><language>en-us</language><copyright>All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Vata Season</title><link>/blog/2020-10-07_vata-season/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-10-07_vata-season/</guid><description>There is a fire in my neck, burning behind my heart and throat.
A clenching of flesh and restriction of movement.
How could this happen. I try and try and try. To do all the things that promise all the outcomes.</description></item><item><title>Courage</title><link>/blog/2020-09-13_a-ride/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-09-13_a-ride/</guid><description>The vibrations rattle my bones and like a seismic shift I can feel everything unfolding.
Centuries deep these wounds are flushed with blood thick and poisoned for far too long. My grandmothers, great grandmothers, great great grandmothers, great great great grandmothers, and beyond - they surround me now.</description></item><item><title>Where Rosemary Flourishes</title><link>/blog/2020-09-12_rosemary/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-09-12_rosemary/</guid><description>When we moved into our new home in January of this year our little Rosemary bush made the move along with us. At the time I thought it was quite a large Rosemary bush; little did I know. Now, just 8 months later it&amp;rsquo;s probably four times the size that it was then.</description></item><item><title>Insects of the Garden</title><link>/blog/2020-09-09_pest-tour/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-09-09_pest-tour/</guid><description>One of my favorite things about gardening is that it encourages an abundance of life and energy where there once was not. The transformation of a humble urban backyard into an oasis of natural activity is truly magical. Life begets life.</description></item><item><title>Hand-Sown &amp; Home-Made</title><link>/blog/2020-09-07_basil-pesto/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-09-07_basil-pesto/</guid><description>Hand sown, home grown, hand picked, hand washed, home-made pesto. That&amp;rsquo;s hard to find in a store. A bounty of basil is a joy in the garden and in the kitchen. This pesto is very easy to make and can be frozen for quick and delicious meals in the depths of winter, when the basil plants are long gone.</description></item><item><title>Insects of our Virginia Garden</title><link>/blog/2020-09-05_insects/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-09-05_insects/</guid><description>Some are friends, some are not, but all are truly beautiful. Nature never ceases to amaze me, with it&amp;rsquo;s diversity of designs and patterns, logic and engineering. Each creature with it&amp;rsquo;s own line in this single song we call uni-verse. This gallery is only a brief collection of all that we witnessed over the summer season.</description></item><item><title>Madre</title><link>/blog/2020-07-22_madre/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-07-22_madre/</guid><description>The truth is just that I care. I can&amp;rsquo;t not care. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how.
The moments between the breath. The silence between calls and texts, where memories bubble to the surface and I let them drip down the pane/pain in my mind and absorb into the atmosphere.</description></item><item><title>Diversity</title><link>/blog/2020-07-21_diversity/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-07-21_diversity/</guid><description>Little plant on it&amp;rsquo;s own, doing it&amp;rsquo;s best but struggling alone.
I plant a friend, or two or three. Together they thrive alongside the arriving birds, worms, and bees. Everybody with their own line in this single song called Universe.</description></item><item><title>I Let Go</title><link>/blog/2020-06-06_let-go/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-06-06_let-go/</guid><description>I let go of formal education because it made it hard to think.
I let go of social media because it made it hard to hear.
I let go of striving for the future because it made it hard to feel.</description></item><item><title>Biblical Rains</title><link>/blog/2020-05-29_biblical-rains/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-05-29_biblical-rains/</guid><description>As my memory serves me, May is always pretty rainy. Two years ago as my husband and I were planning for our early June, outdoor wedding I remember getting to the end of May after nearly 30 days straight rainshowers and wondering if I&amp;rsquo;d made a mistake not planning for anything but the perfect sunny day.</description></item><item><title>Gemini Twins</title><link>/blog/2020-05-20_gemini-twins/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-05-20_gemini-twins/</guid><description>This is our first spring in our new house. I&amp;rsquo;m still learning the rhythms of nature here. Still discovering the beings that also call this little space home. Every morning Isaac and I (or Matt) head down to the back yard, so he can take care of his puppy dog business.</description></item><item><title>Spring Freeze</title><link>/blog/2020-05-11_spring-freeze/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-05-11_spring-freeze/</guid><description>Gardening is an endless conversation with nature. Forever being humbled by a force much greater than myself. Forever learning this waltz. She steps, I step&amp;hellip; maybe one day it will look prettier.
It&amp;rsquo;s May and this is the third night here in Southwest Virginia that we&amp;rsquo;re covering our garden.</description></item><item><title>I, Shakti</title><link>/blog/2020-05-10_i-shakti/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-05-10_i-shakti/</guid><description>I cycle with the moon. We run in parallel, she and I.
I see her as I back bend pre-dusk, watching me over the roof; both waxing onward.
I see her in the evenings, glowing through the crack in the curtains, straight into my pupils dialated in the dark.</description></item><item><title>Contentment</title><link>/blog/2020-05-07_contentment/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-05-07_contentment/</guid><description>Earlier this week I was out in the garden late in the afternoon. The sun was dipping low, flashing between the pines. I was working in one of the tomato beds. Removing volunteer grasses brought in by the straw, and pulling various weeds and things.</description></item><item><title>Cherry Bell</title><link>/blog/2020-04-22_cherry-bell/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-04-22_cherry-bell/</guid><description>I love radishes. I love them as a snack, in salads, and roasted. This is our first year trying them out in the garden and I&amp;rsquo;m both impressed and delighted. My only complaint is that I didn&amp;rsquo;t plant enough of them the first succession.</description></item><item><title>Tomatoes Are In</title><link>/blog/2020-04-29_tomatoes-are-in/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-04-29_tomatoes-are-in/</guid><description>Yesterday afternoon I planted 12 of our tomato plants in the raised bed gardens. It took me a few days to debate over the perfect timing; too soon and the cold will stunt the growth; too late and the high heat of summer will challenge the fruit.</description></item><item><title>Morning Reflections</title><link>/blog/2020-04-25_morning-reflections/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-04-25_morning-reflections/</guid><description>The thoughts swirl and then settle, like a snow globe shaken for a season and then set aside.
Soften the face, the eyes, the lips, and tongue. Like a drawing of curtains, the light pours in.
The tip of my index finger touches the tip of my thumb; gently, like in the way butterfly wings were attached to the thorax when the creator built the prototype.</description></item><item><title>Spring Is For Greens</title><link>/blog/2020-04-24_spring-greens/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-04-24_spring-greens/</guid><description>I spent the afternoon re-organizing our &amp;ldquo;greens&amp;rdquo; bed. Pulling the straw off, lifting grass and henbit out and sorting through what&amp;rsquo;s what. Seeds shift in the wind and rain, moving out of the perfect line you hope to create. Or perhaps the earth worms and Armadillidiidae have some kind of game they play called, &amp;ldquo;rearrange the seeds, as to confuse the lady.</description></item><item><title>Expansion</title><link>/blog/2020-04-23_expansion/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-04-23_expansion/</guid><description>Energy always moving. In me. Through me.
Inhale expand; exhale contract; I find stillness.
Turning the soil with my hands; sweet and smells like home. Earthy and rich and vibrating. My cells talking with the cells in the soil. A conversation I can only feel.</description></item><item><title>A No-Plan Dinner</title><link>/blog/2020-04-20_no-plan-dinner/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-04-20_no-plan-dinner/</guid><description>Cooking is one of my very favorite means of creativity. Perhaps this is why I enjoy gardening so much, the pre-req to a good meal. I think getting lost in something that brings you joy is one of the simplest and most true forms of meditation.</description></item><item><title>From Seed We Start</title><link>/blog/2020-04-19_seed-we-start/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-04-19_seed-we-start/</guid><description>There is something untangibly magical about starting plants from seed. There is a rhythm to the process: curating the perfect soil blend, dipping a finger into the soil, dropping the seed, covering, watering, warming, lighting, watching, and adjusting; witnessing and experiencing.</description></item><item><title>On Starting Lavender</title><link>/blog/2020-04-18_starting-lavender/</link><author>Ruth Reyer</author><pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/2020-04-18_starting-lavender/</guid><description>I was gifted a seed packet of lavender this season. I&amp;rsquo;d never heard of starting lavender from seed. Obviously people do it, but I&amp;rsquo;d always understood it most easily propagated through cuttings. A few years ago, back at our rented farmhouse, I did cuttings from an existing lavender plant.</description></item></channel></rss>